# CATHERINE KIM

(703) 309-7653 catkimyj@gmail.com New York, NY PORTFOLIO GITHUB LINKEDIN ANGELLIST

## SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, SQL, SQLite3, PostgreSQL, Webpack, jQuery, Git, Heroku, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

## **PROJECTS**

PROFFERLY (MongoDB, Express.js, React/Redux, Node.js, Google Maps API, AWS, HTML5, CSS3)

live | github

A volunteer app born during the COVID-19 pandemic, Profferly is a platform for the community formed around lending a hand

- Collaborated with three other engineers using Git workflow practices, to manage branches and pull requests in order to avoid merge conflicts and maximize group productivity.
- Managed frontend development as frontend lead. HTML5 and CSS3 were applied, along with webkit keyframes, to create custom
  animations and loader animations for smooth page load and enhanced user experience. Utilization of the AOS library allowed for
  animate-on-scroll effects for loading posts, improving interactivity and responsiveness.
- Created promise-based Axios requests via Express.js routes to work alongside React props and Amazon Web Services S3 (AWS), enabling users to create posts and comments with optional image upload.
- Incorporated Google Maps alongside onClick event listeners, allowing users to create markers stored as data in MongoDB to populate map on render.

WORDPLAY (Rails, React/Redux, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, AWS)

live I github

A single-page, React-Redux spoken-word and poetry annotation app built on a RESTful JSON Rails API - a clone of the Genius app

- Built user authentication system with BCrypt using Rails and React Router for user's account to be validated for protected routes. Implementation of client cookies permit server to retrieve user login to persist across sessions.
- Engineered custom functions by integrating window and selection properties, to extract and capture user selection and user input. Users have the ability to highlight text and save an annotation to the selection.
- Utilized React lifecycles methods to fetch user-input data from Redux store, loading all user annotations for each poem show page.
- Incorporated Amazon Web Services S3 (AWS) with Ruby on Rails Active Storage Blobs to reduce server load and increase scalability.

#### **DEPTH PERCEPTION** (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Anime.js)

live | github

The idea of letting go and achieving deeper meditation and higher consciousness, formulated into a visual app using timed animations

- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Anime.js library to apply timed animations to user-input text via custom functions, which envelops each character in an HTML span tag, and sets duration and delay per character depending on lengths of input and music.
- Designed and styled via CSS and keyframe animations to execute subtle and gradual transitions to showcase soft aesthetics.

#### MINTBOT (JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Botkit.ai, ResumeJSON)

live | github

Using a parsed JSON file of a working professional's resume, MintBot represents the professional to chat with recruiters

- Created a chat bot using Botkit.ai to greet and converse with recruiters and potential employers using a parsed JSON file, formulated via Linkedin profile and ResumeJSON.
- Constructed custom function to recognize misspellings by one or two characters in keywords recognized by chat bot.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Founder / Designer, Forsythia Studio

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2019

- Designed, modified code, oversaw traffic analysis, and managed e-commerce website and social platforms.
- Designed 25+ garments per collection for at least two collections per year.
- Regularly communicated with factories, freelancers, contractors, PR teams, and agencies.
- Retouched all photos and created graphics for the company website and promotions.

#### First Creative Pattern Maker, Marchesa

Nov. 2018 - Nov. 2019

- Drafted patterns for 10+ garments per season for six collections per year, and supervised the process and execution.
- Attended all production meetings to analyze garments for fit and technical errors.
- Managed 6+ sewers, and mentored 3+ interns and a junior pattern maker in technical and non-technical skills in the atelier.

#### Assistant Designer / First Pattern Maker, Christian Siriano

Sept. 2013 - Mar. 2017

- Assisted in design execution and worked closely with founder Christian Siriano.
- Patterned garments for five collections per year, each collection consisting of an average of 50 looks.
- Constructed patterns of custom garments for private clients and celebrities.
- Managed studio and communicated with the production team for efficient garment production.

## **EDUCATION**

Software Engineering - App Academy

BFA in Fashion Design - Fashion Institute of Technology

Minor - Art History, French

Graduated July 2020 Graduated May 2013

,

**Dietetics Program - James Madison University** 

Aug. 2007 - May 2009